

PRODUCT & DIGITAL DESIGNER

SKILLS

Technology: HTML 4/5, CSS 2/3, JavaScript, jQuery, jQuery UI, PHP

Systems: WordPress, Jekyll, Marketo, SalesForce, MailChimp, Aprimo, Eloqua, SharePoint

Applications: Sketch, Adobe XD, Marvel, Invision, Balsamiq, SVN, Git, Fiddler, InDesign, Photoshop, Illustrator

Process: Wireframing, Prototyping, Responsive design, High-fidelity mockups

Delivery: Cross-browser compliance, Fluid grids, Cross-client compliance, SEO, Print-ready markup

Other: Photo retouching, Photography, Copy writing, Illustration, Iconography

PORTFOLIO

- behance.net/danielrajendran
- in linkedin.com/in/danielrajendran

CONTACT

- 07708698413
- danonthe.net

OTHER

- twitter.com/danrajendran
- instagram.com/danrajendran

REFERENCES

Available on request

ABOUT

I'm a multi-format designer with eight years of experience working in fast-paced tech companies. I've been with a start-up as it went from 20 people in a cramped London office to more than 150 people with offices in 3 countries and news coverage in Forbes. In my different roles I've gained experience working across many design mediums, and over time I've found my passion is to design and build beautiful things, from icons and apps to posters and products.

I'm happiest as part of a team where I can learn from others and improve my own skills. I've learned from experience that research and data gathering are inherent to making good design, and that collaborative iteration is a key part of my role. I've got a proven ability to deliver on time, relish learning new skills, and always strive to embrace challenges outside of my comfort zone.

EXPERIENCE



Content and Code - *Product Designer*June 2017 - March 2019

- Was a key part of driving Fresh, the company's Intranet-In-A-Box, through several major product
 milestones, designing key new features that improved usability and increased competitiveness
- Designed the first iteration of the Fresh Mobile app for iOS and Android
- Supported a major platform transition to rebuild Fresh using Modern SharePoint
- Completely redesigned the *Content and Code* and *Fresh* commercial websites to improve user flow and site load times, and reduce overhead caused by over-reliance on WordPress plugins
- Lead a project to update the *Fresh* visual brand, adapting the original pop-art styling to be usable in more situations and formats, without sacrificing the unique visual identity
- Designed new features and layouts for Fresh, updating existing UI components to suit
- Supported the Bids team by designing custom product designs for potential new clients



DataSift - Front-End Developer / UX Designer

January 2015 - December 2016

- Played an instrumental part in launching our Facebook Topic Data platform, creating new web
 content and print collateral, as well as co-ordinating launch of said content
- Lead a project to move legacy internal sites from Drupal to WordPress for easier management
- Ran 'Lunch and Learn' sessions about how design and branding serves the business
- Designed new lead tracking and scoring systems to more greatly improve website lead quality
- Responsible for design, coding, QA, and maintenance for all commercial websites
- $\bullet\,$ Assisted the product team with visual design and UX prototyping for a new product offering
- Designed numerous ebooks, one pagers, banners, and other sales and marketing collateral



Huddle - Web Designer

January 2010 - December 2014

- Acted as the only design and development resource for the commercial arm of the company
- Lead a team that redesigned the home page and free trial process to increase lead gen 180%
- Handled end to end process for the marketing site, blog, and helpdesk, including page design, coding, QA, deployment and maintenance, as well as occasional copywriting and illustration
- Assisted in a complete company rebrand, and then lead a full redesign of the marketing site

EDUCATION



 $\begin{tabular}{ll} \textbf{Goldsmiths, University of London -} \textit{BSc Computing and Interaction Design} \\ \textbf{September 2006 -} \textit{August 2009} \\ \end{tabular}$

Focused on digital design principles such as web design, user experience and interaction design. My final project was a device that could be used to manipulate 3D models in real-time.